Rakesh Joshi

Senior Software Engineer

A senior front-end developer with over 8 years of experience, specialising in web application development, Agile, Scrum, and UX design. Experience of Managing a small team to design Single Page Application using Angular and React.

ioshirakesh165@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/rakesh-joshi-8142a2150

9971308902

github.com/joshirakesh165

WORK EXPERIENCE (8 YEARS)

Senior Software Engineer

Ciena India

01/2022 - Present

Pune

Senior Software Engineer

Airtel Xlabs

05/2020 - 01/2022 Gurgaon

Associate Lead, Technology

Nagarro Softwares

01/2018 - 04/2020

Gurgaon, India

Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

04/2016 - 01/2018

Noida,India

ROLES/RESPONSIBILITIES

As an individual contributor

- Involved in developing responsive User Interface and Single Page Application.
- Analyze common services, component across the application.
- Handle initial setup kick start of application, git configuration, logger environment setups.
- Unit testing with Jasmine karma.
- Implementation of analytics for website to monitor webpage traffic
- Code Review and Architectural Discussion In Front End
- Designing reusable components to be used across multiple projects.
- Passionate about building great solutions.
- Expertise in writing and reviewing great-quality code.

COMPETENCIES & SKILLS



PROJECTS

E- commerce for surveillance (08/2020 - Present)

 E commerce website which provides its customer to view and purchase surveillance product.

Risk Management Based project (04/2018 - 07/2020)

Started as Angular 4 project recently migrated to Angular 5.
Project involved handling of large set of data at front end and various complex operations..

Back Office Application (04/2017 - 12/2018)

 Project is a modernization of an existing application from Visual Basic to Angular 2. The application facilitates crew staff and managers on the cruise.

Fun Time Modernization (08/2016 - 03/2017)

 Project is a modernization of an existing application from Visual Basic to Angular 2. The application facilitates crew staff and managers on the cruise.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application
Uttarakhand Technical University

05/2012 - 05/2015

Uttarakhand, 75 %

Bachelor of Science

HNB Garhwal, University

04/2009 - 05/2012

Uttrakhand,65 %

Intermediate

Uttarakhand Board

05/2009 Uttrakhand, 68%

High School

Uttarakhand Board

05/2007 Uttrakhand,75%